https://www.linkedin.com/in/luke-gunders/

https://luke-gunders.netlify.app/

https://github.com/lgunds6



Luke Gunders

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I am an accomplished professional with 7 years of experience working for Alinta Energy and Origin Energy in a variety of Analyst roles. Whilst working as a Change Management Analyst, I had the opportunity to work on software development projects. Based on this experience, I decided to embark on a career change, enrolling in a course to enable me to work as a Junior Software Developer.

In February 2022, I graduated with a Diploma of Information Technology from Coder Academy (Academy of Information Technology), with a focus on software development. I then obtained a position at Clear Dynamics working as a CX Delivery Engineer, with a focus on front-end development. I also undertook and currently hold a AGSVA Baseline security clearance. I am currently looking for a new role as a Junior Software Developer, focusing on front-end development where I can continue to learn and grow.

Technical Skills

- JavaScript
- Ruby on Rails
- HTML
- CSS

- React.js
- PostgreSQL
- TypeScript
- Agile development methodologies

Education

2021 - 2022 (GRADUATED FEBRUARY 2022)

Diploma of Information Technology / Coder Academy (Academy of Information Technology)

Coder Academy offers Australia's only accredited full stack software development course, graduating with a Diploma of Information Technology. In this course, I have developed practical and real-world programming skills, with a particular focus on building and deploying applications using JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS3.

- Introduction to Web
- Information Systems
- Foundation Programming
- Programming I

- Database Systems
- Introduction to Software Engineering
- Discrete Mathematics
- Programming II

Professional Experience

MAY 2022 - NOV 2022

CX Delivery Engineer / Clear Dynamics

- Successfully designed and delivered features for an Australian Government client project that included a public-facing self-service portal, as well as a back-end account management portal.
- Obtained AGSVA Baseline security clearance.
- Develop and deliver features to meet customer requirements, utilising, JavaScript, React.js, TypeScript, CSS & HTML.
- Participate in daily standups and provide timely updates on progress of assigned work.
- Contribute to release planning, release notes, and deployments by assisting the tech lead and Implementation Manager to ensure a high-quality release.
- Work with designers to implement high quality UX/UI.
- Ensure the functionality, usability, accessibility, performance, and security of features meet expectations.
- Collaborate with QA officers to complete test planning, design, and automation.

MAR 2022 - MAY 2022

Front End Developer (Internship) / Safety Champion Software

- Work on assigned tickets to successfully fix bugs identified by testing team.
- Attend and contribute to daily standups.
- Apply front end development skills learnt through Coder Academy course in a realworld environment.
- Developed skills in AngularJS to complement broader front end development skills.
- Worked collaboratively within the software development team to successfully meet deadlines.

NOV 2020 - JUL 2021

Functional Lead - Billing / Alinta Energy

- Lead a team of three Billing Analysts.
- Own, manage and prioritise billing defects & issues, manage enhancement and improvement projects to ensure alignment with customer operations strategy and the broader objectives of Alinta Energy East Coast business.
- Create and maintain procedural documentation.
- Own and deliver process maps and work instructions for the function.
- Provide data operational insights to support business key decision making.
- Key analysis as required to enable improvements to daily process mechanisms and customer experience.
- Work across all key business teams supporting daily activities.

MAR 2019 - NOV 2020

Retail Transformation – Change Management Analyst / Origin Energy

- Conduct change analysis and change impact assessments to support change management activities.
- Build and maintain strong relationships with internal and external stakeholders to enhance business relationships and project delivery and to understand and manage the impacts of the change and project implementation plan.
- Work collaboratively with all operational business groups to understand current and future state and to ensure business requirements are translated into documentation.
- Develop and deliver effective change plans and change reporting in conjunction with the Change Lead to document and communicate change activities.

AUG 2018 - MAR 2019

Retail Program Management Analyst / Origin Energy

- Supporting operating rhythms and processes to help accelerate delivery of key strategic initiatives.
- Managing information required to support key retail governance forums and ensuring required compliance documentation is maintained.
- Supporting retail planning and prioritisation and maintaining the retail integrated roadmap.
- Identifying interdependencies between strategic initiatives and ensuring alignment across the change program.

MAR 2018 - AUG 2018

Change Analyst - Lead / Origin Energy

- Assess all initiatives to ensure all customer touch points and business impacts are documented and worked through.
- Providing the business recommendations on their strategic initiatives to ensure a positive customer experience.
- Provide support to initiators of change to assist them in gaining endorsement through the retail activity approval forum and frontline working groups.
- Post implementation review of changes to ensure their effectiveness and success.

JUL 2014 - MAR 2018

Quality Analyst / Origin Energy

- Monitor and support Origin's retail departments against Business and Industry requirements.
- Provide analysis to the business to identify opportunities and strengthen customer experience.
- Customer Service and Customer Experience matter expert.
- Insights to support continuous improvement within processes.

Portfolio & Projects

Personal Website / HTML5 & CSS3 https://luke-gunders.netlify.app/

I have built my personal website using HTML5 and CSS3. This website demonstrates my web development skills using HTML and CSS to develop a working website. This website will evolve throughout my career to showcase my skills and experience.

Calorie Counter Application / Terminal application - Ruby https://github.com/lgunds6/T1A3 terminal application/tree/master

Terminal application built using Ruby. This application is a calorie calculator. It takes user input and calculates the recommended daily calories that the user should consume based on user fitness goals and activity level.

Marketplace Application / Ruby on Rails & PostgreSQL https://hangtenboards.herokuapp.com/

Two-sided Marketplace built using Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL. This application demonstrates my ability to develop a two-sided marketplace using Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL. It allows a user to sell items as well as purchase items from the marketplace.

Soft Skills

- Stakeholder engagement
- Communication
- Problem solving
- Team player
- Adaptable

- Fast learner
- Leadership
- Analytical skills
- Time management
- Project management

Referees

- Upon request, professional referees can be provided from all educational and professional experiences including Clear Dynamics, Coder Academy, Safety Champion Software, Alinta Energy and Origin Energy.
- Personal referees are also available upon request.